export const history =    [
{
"category": "History",
"type": "multiple",
"difficulty": "hard",
"question": "Pianist%20Fr%C3%A9d%C3%A9ric%20Chopin%20was%20a%20composer%20of%20which%20musical%20era%3F",
"correct_answer": "Romantic",
"incorrect_answers": [
"Classic",
"Baroque",
"Renaissance"
]
},
{
"category": "History",
"type": "multiple",
"difficulty": "hard",
"question": "Which%20naval%20battle%20was%20considered%20the%20turning%20point%20of%20the%20Pacific%20Ocean%20Theater%20during%20World%20War%202%3F",
"correct_answer": "Battle%20of%20Midway",
"incorrect_answers": [
"Attack%20on%20Truk%20Island",
"Attack%20on%20Pearl%20Harbor",
"Battle%20of%20the%20Coral%20Sea"
]
},
{
"category": "History",
"type": "multiple",
"difficulty": "hard",
"question": "In%20the%20year%201900%2C%20what%20were%20the%20most%20popular%20first%20names%20given%20to%20boy%20and%20girl%20babies%20born%20in%20the%20United%20States%3F",
"correct_answer": "John%20and%20Mary",
"incorrect_answers": [
"Joseph%20and%20Catherine",
"William%20and%20Elizabeth",
"George%20and%20Anne"
]
},
{
"category": "History",
"type": "multiple",
"difficulty": "hard",
"question": "What%20was%20the%20name%20of%20the%20spy%20ring%20that%20helped%20the%20United%20States%20win%20the%20Revolutionary%20War%3F",
"correct_answer": "Culper%20Ring",
"incorrect_answers": [
"New%20York%20Spy%20Ring",
"Washington%27s%20Spies",
"Unnamed"
]
},
{
"category": "History",
"type": "multiple",
"difficulty": "hard",
"question": "What%20year%20was%20Canada%20founded%20in%3F",
"correct_answer": "1867",
"incorrect_answers": [
"1798",
"1859",
"1668"
]
},
{
"category": "History",
"type": "multiple",
"difficulty": "hard",
"question": "On%20which%20day%20did%20ARPANET%20suffer%20a%204%20hour%20long%20network%20crash%3F",
"correct_answer": "October%2027%2C%201980",
"incorrect_answers": [
"November%2021%2C%201969",
"October%2029%2C%201969",
"December%209%2C%201991"
]
},
{
"category": "History",
"type": "multiple",
"difficulty": "hard",
"question": "What%20did%20the%20first%20vending%20machines%20in%20the%20early%201880%27s%20dispense%3F",
"correct_answer": "Post%20cards",
"incorrect_answers": [
"Alcohol",
"Cigarettes",
"Sodas%20"
]
},
{
"category": "History",
"type": "multiple",
"difficulty": "hard",
"question": "When%20did%20Canada%20leave%20the%20confederation%20to%20become%20their%20own%20nation%3F",
"correct_answer": "July%201st%2C%201867",
"incorrect_answers": [
"July%201st%2C%201763",
"July%201st%2C%201832",
"July%201st%2C%201902"
]
},
{
"category": "History",
"type": "multiple",
"difficulty": "hard",
"question": "When%20was%20the%20SS%20or%20Schutzstaffel%20established%3F",
"correct_answer": "April%204th%2C%201925",
"incorrect_answers": [
"September%201st%2C%201941",
"March%208th%2C%201935",
"February%2021st%2C%201926"
]
},
{
"category": "History",
"type": "multiple",
"difficulty": "hard",
"question": "During%20the%20Wars%20of%20the%20Roses%20%281455%20-%201487%29%20which%20Englishman%20was%20dubbed%20%22the%20Kingmaker%22%3F",
"correct_answer": "Richard%20Neville",
"incorrect_answers": [
"Richard%20III",
"Henry%20V",
"Thomas%20Warwick"
]
},
{
"category": "History",
"type": "multiple",
"difficulty": "hard",
"question": "When%20was%20Adolf%20Hitler%20appointed%20as%20Chancellor%20of%20Germany%3F",
"correct_answer": "January%2030%2C%201933",
"incorrect_answers": [
"September%201%2C%201939",
"February%2027%2C%201933",
"October%206%2C%201939"
]
},
{
"category": "History",
"type": "multiple",
"difficulty": "hard",
"question": "Bohdan%20Khmelnytsky%20was%20which%20of%20the%20following%3F",
"correct_answer": "Leader%20of%20the%20Ukrainian%20Cossacks",
"incorrect_answers": [
"General%20Secretary%20of%20the%20Communist%20Party%20of%20the%20USSR",
"Prince%20of%20Wallachia",
"Grand%20Prince%20of%20Novgorod"
]
},
{
"category": "History",
"type": "multiple",
"difficulty": "hard",
"question": "Which%20one%20of%20these%20rulers%20did%20not%20belong%20to%20the%20Habsburg%20dynasty%3F",
"correct_answer": "Philip%20V",
"incorrect_answers": [
"Charles%20V",
"Philip%20II",
"Francis%20Joseph"
]
},
{
"category": "History",
"type": "multiple",
"difficulty": "hard",
"question": "How%20many%20sonatas%20did%20Ludwig%20van%20Beethoven%20write%3F",
"correct_answer": "32",
"incorrect_answers": [
"50",
"31",
"21"
]
},
{
"category": "History",
"type": "multiple",
"difficulty": "hard",
"question": "During%20the%20Roman%20Triumvirate%20of%2042%20BCE%2C%20what%20region%20of%20the%20Roman%20Republic%20was%20given%20to%20Lepidus%3F",
"correct_answer": "Hispania%20",
"incorrect_answers": [
"Italia",
"Gallia",
"Asia"
]
},
{
"category": "History",
"type": "multiple",
"difficulty": "hard",
"question": "The%20Second%20Boer%20War%20in%201899%20was%20fought%20where%3F",
"correct_answer": "South%20Africa",
"incorrect_answers": [
"Argentina",
"Nepal",
"Bulgaria"
]
},
{
"category": "History",
"type": "multiple",
"difficulty": "hard",
"question": "In%20which%20year%20did%20the%20Tokyo%20Subway%20Sarin%20Attack%20occur%3F",
"correct_answer": "1995",
"incorrect_answers": [
"2001",
"2011",
"1991"
]
},
{
"category": "History",
"type": "multiple",
"difficulty": "hard",
"question": "Who%20invented%20the%20%22Flying%20Shuttle%22%20in%201738%3B%20one%20of%20the%20key%20developments%20in%20the%20industrialization%20of%20weaving%3F",
"correct_answer": "John%20Kay",
"incorrect_answers": [
"James%20Hargreaves",
"Richard%20Arkwright",
"John%20Deere"
]
},
{
"category": "History",
"type": "multiple",
"difficulty": "hard",
"question": "What%20year%20was%20the%20United%20States%20Declaration%20of%20Independence%20signed%3F",
"correct_answer": "1776",
"incorrect_answers": [
"1775",
"1774",
"1777"
]
},
{
"category": "History",
"type": "multiple",
"difficulty": "hard",
"question": "When%20did%20Lithuania%20declare%20independence%20from%20the%20Soviet%20Union%3F",
"correct_answer": "March%2011th%2C%201990",
"incorrect_answers": [
"December%2025th%2C%201991",
"December%205th%2C%201991",
"April%2020th%2C%201989"
]
},
{
"category": "History",
"type": "multiple",
"difficulty": "hard",
"question": "What%20was%20Napoleon%20Bonaparte%27s%20name%20before%20he%20changed%20it%3F",
"correct_answer": "Napoleone%20di%20Buonaparte",
"incorrect_answers": [
"Naapolion%20van%20Bonijpaart",
"Napole%C3%A3o%20do%20Boaparte",
"Napoleona%20de%20Buenoparte"
]
},
{
"category": "History",
"type": "multiple",
"difficulty": "hard",
"question": "The%20Hagia%20Sophia%20was%20commissioned%20by%20which%20emperor%20of%20the%20Byzantine%20Empire%3F",
"correct_answer": "Justinian%20I",
"incorrect_answers": [
"Constantine%20IV",
"Arcadius",
"Theodosius%20the%20Great"
]
},
{
"category": "History",
"type": "multiple",
"difficulty": "hard",
"question": "During%20the%20Spanish%20Civil%20War%20%281936%29%2C%20Francisco%20Franco%20fought%20for%20which%20political%20faction%3F",
"correct_answer": "Nationalist%20Spain",
"incorrect_answers": [
"Republican%20Spain",
"Popular%20Front",
"Papal%20State"
]
},
{
"category": "History",
"type": "multiple",
"difficulty": "hard",
"question": "What%20was%20found%20in%201946%20by%20two%20young%20shepards%20near%20a%20cave%3F",
"correct_answer": "Dead%20Sea%20Scrolls",
"incorrect_answers": [
"The%20Blackbeard%20Chest",
"Sheep",
"The%20First%20Oaxaca%20Cave%20Sleeper"
]
},
{
"category": "History",
"type": "multiple",
"difficulty": "hard",
"question": "Who%20was%20the%20President%20of%20the%20United%20States%20during%20the%20signing%20of%20the%20Gadsden%20Purchase%3F",
"correct_answer": "Franklin%20Pierce",
"incorrect_answers": [
"Andrew%20Johnson",
"Abraham%20Lincoln",
"James%20Polk"
]
},
{
"category": "History",
"type": "multiple",
"difficulty": "hard",
"question": "When%20was%20the%20city%20of%20Rome%2C%20Italy%20founded%3F",
"correct_answer": "753%20BCE",
"incorrect_answers": [
"902%20BCE",
"524%20BCE",
"697%20BCE"
]
},
{
"category": "History",
"type": "multiple",
"difficulty": "hard",
"question": "How%20many%20women%20joined%20the%20United%20States%20Armed%20Services%20during%20World%20War%20II%3F",
"correct_answer": "350%2C000",
"incorrect_answers": [
"225%2C000",
"100%2C000",
"500%2C000"
]
},
{
"category": "History",
"type": "multiple",
"difficulty": "hard",
"question": "What%20was%20the%20aim%20of%20the%20%22Umbrella%20Revolution%22%20in%20Hong%20Kong%20in%202014%3F",
"correct_answer": "Genuine%20universal%20suffrage",
"incorrect_answers": [
"Gaining%20Independence",
"Go%20back%20under%20British%20Rule",
"Lower%20taxes"
]
},
{
"category": "History",
"type": "multiple",
"difficulty": "hard",
"question": "What%20was%20the%20original%20name%20of%20New%20York%20City%3F",
"correct_answer": "New%20Amsterdam",
"incorrect_answers": [
"New%20London",
"New%20Paris",
"New%20Rome"
]
},
{
"category": "History",
"type": "multiple",
"difficulty": "hard",
"question": "What%20was%20the%20name%20of%20the%20German%20offensive%20operation%20in%20October%201941%20to%20take%20Moscow%20before%20winter%3F",
"correct_answer": "Operation%20Typhoon",
"incorrect_answers": [
"Operation%20Sunflower",
"Operation%20Barbarossa",
"Case%20Blue"
]
},
{
"category": "History",
"type": "multiple",
"difficulty": "hard",
"question": "When%20was%20the%20%22Siege%20of%20Leningrad%22%20lifted%20during%20World%20War%20II%3F",
"correct_answer": "January%201944",
"incorrect_answers": [
"September%201943",
"November%201943",
"March%201944"
]
},
{
"category": "History",
"type": "multiple",
"difficulty": "hard",
"question": "Which%20of%20the%20following%20was%20not%20one%20of%20Joseph%20Stalin%27s%20ten%20blows%20during%20World%20War%20II%3F",
"correct_answer": "Vistula-Oder%20Offensive",
"incorrect_answers": [
"Crimean%20Offensive",
"Leningrad-Novgorod%20Offensive",
"Operation%20Bagration"
]
},
{
"category": "History",
"type": "multiple",
"difficulty": "hard",
"question": "What%20did%20the%20abbreviation%20%22RMS%22%20stand%20for%20in%20the%20RMS%20Titanic%20in%201912%3F",
"correct_answer": "Royal%20Mail%20Ship",
"incorrect_answers": [
"Royal%20Majesty%20Service",
"Regular%20Maritime%20Schedule%20",
"Regulated%20Maelstrom%20Sensor"
]
},
{
"category": "History",
"type": "multiple",
"difficulty": "hard",
"question": "In%20addition%20to%20his%20career%20as%20an%20astrologer%20and%20%22prophet%22%2C%20Nostradamus%20published%20a%201555%20treatise%20that%20included%20a%20section%20on%20what%3F",
"correct_answer": "Making%20jams%20and%20jellies",
"incorrect_answers": [
"Teaching%20parrots%20to%20talk",
"Cheating%20at%20card%20games",
"Digging%20graves"
]
},
{
"category": "History",
"type": "multiple",
"difficulty": "hard",
"question": "Before%20the%20American%20colonies%20switched%20to%20the%20Gregorian%20calendar%20in%201752%2C%20on%20what%20date%20did%20their%20new%20year%20start%3F",
"correct_answer": "March%2025th",
"incorrect_answers": [
"June%201st",
"September%2025th",
"December%201st"
]
},
{
"category": "History",
"type": "multiple",
"difficulty": "hard",
"question": "From%201940%20to%201942%2C%20what%20was%20the%20capital-in-exile%20of%20Free%20France%20%3F",
"correct_answer": "Brazzaville",
"incorrect_answers": [
"Algiers",
"Paris",
"Tunis"
]
},
{
"category": "History",
"type": "multiple",
"difficulty": "hard",
"question": "The%20ancient%20city%20of%20Chich%C3%A9n%20Itz%C3%A1%20was%20built%20by%20which%20civilization%3F",
"correct_answer": "Mayans",
"incorrect_answers": [
"Aztecs",
"Incas",
"Toltecs"
]
},
{
"category": "History",
"type": "multiple",
"difficulty": "hard",
"question": "Who%20assassinated%20President%20James%20A.%20Garfield%3F",
"correct_answer": "Charles%20Guiteau",
"incorrect_answers": [
"Sirhan%20Sirhan",
"Leon%20Czolgosz",
"John%20Wilkes%20Booth"
]
},
{
"category": "History",
"type": "multiple",
"difficulty": "hard",
"question": "The%20pantheon%20in%20Rome%20was%20used%20to%20worship%20what%20god%3F",
"correct_answer": "Any%20god%20they%20wanted",
"incorrect_answers": [
"Athena",
"Zeus",
"Both%20Athena%20and%20Zeus"
]
},
{
"category": "History",
"type": "multiple",
"difficulty": "hard",
"question": "During%20World%20War%20I%2C%20which%20nation%27s%20monarchs%20were%20blood%20related%3F",
"correct_answer": "England%2C%20Germany%2C%20Russia",
"incorrect_answers": [
"France%2C%20Russia%2C%20Germany",
"Serbia%2C%20Russia%2C%20Croatia",
"Germany%2C%20Spain%2C%20Austria"
]
},
{
"category": "History",
"type": "multiple",
"difficulty": "hard",
"question": "Which%20U.S.%20president%20was%20said%20to%20have%20been%20too%20honest%20to%20lie%20to%20his%20father%20about%20chopping%20down%20a%20cherry%20tree%3F",
"correct_answer": "George%20Washington",
"incorrect_answers": [
"Abraham%20Lincoln",
"Thomas%20Jefferson",
"James%20Monroe"
]
},
{
"category": "History",
"type": "multiple",
"difficulty": "hard",
"question": "The%20Bohemian%20Revolt%20%281618-1620%29%20started%20after%20Protestants%20in%20Prague%20did%20what%20to%20their%20Catholic%20Lords%20Regents%3F",
"correct_answer": "Threw%20them%20out%20of%20a%20window",
"incorrect_answers": [
"Insulted%20their%20mothers",
"Locked%20them%20in%20stockades",
"Hung%20them."
]
},
{
"category": "History",
"type": "multiple",
"difficulty": "hard",
"question": "After%20the%201516%20Battle%20of%20Marj%20Dabiq%2C%20the%20Ottoman%20Empire%20took%20control%20of%20Jerusalem%20from%20which%20sultanate%3F",
"correct_answer": "Mamluk",
"incorrect_answers": [
"Ayyubid",
"Ummayyad",
"Seljuq"
]
},
{
"category": "History",
"type": "multiple",
"difficulty": "hard",
"question": "The%20son%20of%20which%20pope%20supposedly%20held%20a%20lecherous%20f%C3%AAte%20involving%2050%20courtesans%20in%20the%20papal%20palace%3F",
"correct_answer": "Alexander%20VI",
"incorrect_answers": [
"Innocent%20V",
"Urban%20II",
"Pius%20III"
]
},
{
"category": "History",
"type": "multiple",
"difficulty": "hard",
"question": "The%20coat%20of%20arms%20of%20the%20King%20of%20Spain%20contains%20the%20arms%20from%20the%20monarchs%20of%20Castille%2C%20Leon%2C%20Aragon%20and%20which%20other%20former%20Iberian%20kingdom%3F",
"correct_answer": "Navarre",
"incorrect_answers": [
"Galicia",
"Granada",
"Catalonia"
]
},
{
"category": "History",
"type": "multiple",
"difficulty": "hard",
"question": "The%20ontological%20argument%20for%20the%20proof%20of%20God%27s%20existence%20is%20first%20attributed%20to%20whom%3F",
"correct_answer": "Anselm%20of%20Canterbury",
"incorrect_answers": [
"Ren%C3%A9%20Descartes",
"Immanuel%20Kant",
"Aristotle"
]
},
{
"category": "History",
"type": "multiple",
"difficulty": "hard",
"question": "Which%20of%20the%20following%20physicists%20did%20NOT%20work%20on%20the%20Manhattan%20project%3F",
"correct_answer": "Murray%20Gell-Mann",
"incorrect_answers": [
"Richard%20Feynman",
"J.%20Robert%20Oppenheimer",
"John%20Von-Neumann"
]
},
{
"category": "History",
"type": "multiple",
"difficulty": "hard",
"question": "Which%20is%20the%20hull%20NO.%20of%20the%20Fletcher%20class%20destroyer%20Fletcher%3F",
"correct_answer": "DD-445",
"incorrect_answers": [
"DD-992",
"DD-444",
"DD-446"
]
},
{
"category": "History",
"type": "multiple",
"difficulty": "hard",
"question": "Which%20of%20these%20theoretical%20phycisists%20first%20predicted%20the%20existence%20of%20antimatter%3F",
"correct_answer": "Paul%20Dirac",
"incorrect_answers": [
"Niels%20Bohr",
"Albert%20Einstein",
"Werner%20Heisenberg"
]
},
{
"category": "History",
"type": "multiple",
"difficulty": "hard",
"question": "Which%20country%20did%20the%20Eureka%20Rebellion%2C%20an%201856%20battle%20against%20colonial%20rule%2C%20take%20place%20in%3F",
"correct_answer": "Australia",
"incorrect_answers": [
"India",
"Canada",
"Brazil"
]
}
]